<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-03T16:05:14+01:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">hack.lu 2025</title><subtitle>Hack.lu is an open convention/conference where people can discuss about computer security, privacy, information technology and its cultural/technical implication on society. It&apos;s the 19th edition (21st -&gt; 24th October) of hack.lu in Luxembourg.</subtitle><author><name>hack.lu</name></author><entry><title type="html">Call for papers is now open for hack.lu 2025</title><link href="/blog/hack.lu-2025-call-for-papers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Call for papers is now open for hack.lu 2025" /><published>2024-12-03T10:39:55+01:00</published><updated>2024-12-03T10:39:55+01:00</updated><id>/blog/hack.lu-2025-call-for-papers</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/hack.lu-2025-call-for-papers/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;hacklu-2025-call-for-papers-including-cti-summit&quot;&gt;hack.lu 2025 Call for Papers (including cti-summit)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the hack.lu convention is to provide an open and free playground where people can discuss the implications of new technologies in society. hack.lu is a balanced mix convention where technical and non-technical people can meet and share all kinds of information freely. The convention will be held in the Grand-Duchy of Luxembourg in October (21-24.10.2024). The most significant new discoveries about computer network attacks and defenses, open-source security solutions, and pragmatic real-world security experiences will be presented in a four-day series of informative tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hack.lu includes the Cyber and Threat Intelligence Summit gathering all the experts, analysts, users, and contributors to cyber and threat intelligence at large. A strong focus will be given to projects bridging intelligence communities together and also open-source related projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite you to submit papers, lightning talks, and workshop proposals for selection by the hack.lu technical review committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;topics-of-interest&quot;&gt;Topics of Interest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software Engineering and Security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honeypots/Honeynets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spyware, Phishing, and Botnets (Distributed attacks)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Newly discovered vulnerabilities in software and hardware&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Electronic/Digital Privacy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wireless Network and Security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attacks on Information Systems and/or Digital Information Storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Electronic Voting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free Software and Security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessment of Computer, Electronic Devices, and Information Systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Standards for Information Security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legal and Social Aspect of Information Security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security in Information Retrieval&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network Security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Malware Analysis and Reversing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forensics and Anti-Forensics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offensive (and counter-offensive) Information Technology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile Communications Security and Vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSIRTs, Incident Analysis and Response&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information Security and Data Mining&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Threats Exchange and Sharing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cti-related-topics&quot;&gt;CTI Related Topics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open source tooling used in threat intelligence including new tools or development of existing tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Threat intelligence processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Successes and failures in creating threat intelligence processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of open-source tools (such as MISP) into SOC, CSIRT, or any security organization or intelligence community to support threat intelligence processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interoperability between threat intelligence tools (open source and proprietary)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improving and evaluating the quality of threat intelligence at large&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share lessons learned in the intelligence domains including analysis processes, analytical methods, and/or techniques&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lessons and challenges while performing intelligence analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Successes and failures in data modeling for intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share experiences in information and intelligence sharing including building communities, tooling, social interactions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improving skills in intelligence domains such as threat analysis, collection, and dissemination&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrating OSINT, HUMINT, *INT into threat intelligence processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above lists of topics are not exhaustive and other related topics are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presentation-format&quot;&gt;Presentation Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format of the talks during hack.lu is composed of a 20-minute maximum presentation with a 10-minute Q&amp;amp;A session. The goal is to foster collaboration and live discussions. The sessions will be video recorded except if the presenter doesn’t accept. Complementary papers, articles, and presentations are highly encouraged for participants who are willing to have more insight about the presentation given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-information&quot;&gt;General Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;date-and-location&quot;&gt;Date and Location&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hack.lu conference will take place physically in Luxembourg (October 21 - 24, 2024) at the&lt;br /&gt;
Parc Hotel Alvisse, 120 Route d’Echternach, L-1453 Luxembourg&lt;br /&gt;
(Long : 49.6399337, Lat : 6.1517228)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;speakers-privileges&quot;&gt;Speakers’ Privileges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the selected talks/presentations/papers, authors will get free access to the conference.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One speaker per talk/workshop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accommodation will be provided (up to 4 nights during the conference). Hotel room must be reserved with a dedicated registration code, and paid in advance as guarantee. The money will be reimbursed during check-out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lunch, beverages, and more during all days of the conference.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reimbursement of travel costs up to 300 EUR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;language&quot;&gt;Language&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The language of the conference is English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;publication-and-rights&quot;&gt;Publication and Rights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors keep the full rights on their publications/papers but give an unrestricted right to redistribute their papers for the hack.lu convention and its related electronic/paper publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can enter proposals until 2025-04-30 11:59 (UTC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.com/hack-lu-2025/cfp&quot;&gt;Edit or view your proposals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.com/hack-lu-2025/cfp&quot;&gt;Submit a proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sponsoring&quot;&gt;Sponsoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If  you  want  to  support  the  initiative  and  gain  visibility  by
sponsoring, please contact us by writing an e-mail to info(AT)hack.lu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about &lt;a href=&quot;/sponsoring&quot;&gt;sponsoring options&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cfp-website-submission&quot;&gt;CfP Website Submission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.com/hack-lu-2025/&quot;&gt;CfP hack.lu 2025 submission website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>hack.lu</name></author><summary type="html">Time to submit a talk, training or workshop to hack.lu</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">hack.lu 2024 Wraps Up a Thrilling 18th Edition with Global Participation and Networking Highlights</title><link href="/blog/hack.lu-2024-wraps-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="hack.lu 2024 Wraps Up a Thrilling 18th Edition with Global Participation and Networking Highlights" /><published>2024-11-04T05:39:55+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T05:39:55+01:00</updated><id>/blog/hack.lu-2024-wraps-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/hack.lu-2024-wraps-up/">&lt;p&gt;Luxembourg, November 04, 2024 – hack.lu, Europe’s central hub for cybersecurity professionals, enthusiasts, and experts, celebrated its 18th successful edition from October 22-25 in Luxembourg, hosting a packed agenda of workshops, trainings, and talks. With over 500 participants from around the world and 75 expert speakers, this year’s conference once again proved to be an essential event in the cybersecurity calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of four days, hack.lu attendees immersed themselves in topics at the forefront of security, intelligence, and privacy. They enjoyed a packed schedule balanced with ample opportunities to connect over coffee breaks, pastries, and thoughtfully prepared lunches. As a priority for hack.lu, exceptional catering played an essential role in keeping energy high and conversations flowing throughout the event. Attendees also actively participated by presenting 26 lightning talks, each allowing speakers to share their experiences in a concise 5-minute format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before the conference, the renowned &lt;a href=&quot;https://flu.xxx/&quot;&gt;hack.lu CTF&lt;/a&gt; took place, with 608 teams participating in challenges organized and designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://flu.xxx/info&quot;&gt;FluxFingers&lt;/a&gt;, the CTF team from Ruhr University Bochum (Germany). During the conference, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacklu.firstseclounge.org/&quot;&gt;hack.lu 2024 challenges&lt;/a&gt; were organized by the &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;FIRST SecLounge SIG volunteers&lt;/a&gt;, offering participants various levels of challenges to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference organizers hosted a speaker’s dinner on the first evening to recognize and celebrate the event’s contributors. On the second day, participants mingled at an independently organized social event, which included fun activities such as PowerPoint karaoke. The third evening featured an invitation to the Cybersecurity Gala, held in collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://cswl.lu/autumn&quot;&gt;Cybersecurity Week Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sascha Rommelfangen, co-organizer of hack.lu, reflects: &lt;em&gt;“We’ve received tremendous positive feedback for this year’s organization. It’s inspiring to see participants join us from across the globe, from Australia to China, Mauritius to the USA. hack.lu is all about fostering connections in a friendly and inclusive setting, and we’re already looking forward to making next year’s event even more memorable.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The talks and videos given during the conference are now publicly available&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://2024.hack.lu/agenda/&quot;&gt;hack.lu website&lt;/a&gt; and as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sVlLjaTY1pc&amp;amp;list=PLwOU9wiTf8XRYD579lHCXFAdAnRDqcVQu&quot;&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With strong support from &lt;a href=&quot;https://2024.hack.lu/sponsoring/&quot;&gt;15 sponsors&lt;/a&gt;, hack.lu 2024 provided a vibrant atmosphere for collaboration and learning. Sponsors and participants alike appreciated the open setting that encouraged interaction and knowledge exchange on the latest cybersecurity challenges and innovations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexandre Dulaunoy, co-founder and main organizer of hack.lu, sums it up: &lt;em&gt;“hack.lu has always been about creating a space where knowledge flows freely and innovation thrives. This year, we saw remarkable ideas emerge from discussions, workshops, and impromptu conversations over coffee or tea. The diversity of voices – from seasoned experts to emerging talents – made this edition incredibly dynamic. We’re honored to facilitate these connections that not only strengthen our community but also push the boundaries of cybersecurity collaboration on a global scale. We look forward to building and improving on this momentum for hack.lu 2025, continuing to shape a future where security and openness go hand in hand.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As hack.lu 2024 concludes, the organizers are already setting their sights on &lt;strong&gt;hack.lu 2025, scheduled for October 21-24, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, promising another year of inspiration, innovation, and community for the global cybersecurity landscape. We would also like to extend our heartfelt thanks to all our sponsors, supporters, volunteers, and participants who helped make hack.lu a remarkable conference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>hack.lu</name></author><summary type="html">hack.lu 2024 Wraps Up a Thrilling 18th Edition with Global Participation and Networking Highlights</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry></feed>